Guide to the New York, Ontario, & Western Railway Co. records, 1868-1956
New York, Ontario, & Western Railway Co. records, 1868-1956
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York, Ontario, & Western Railway Co. records, 1868-1956.
1949
William Floyd, Helmer 1926-,
4 cubic ft.
Bound volumes, maps, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes volumes of copies of deeds showing trackage locations; volumes of dispatchers' diaries; volumes of engineers' survey books; one volume of official notices of schedule and route changes; map and survey; timetable; map and profile of the Pecksport Loop line.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes 7 volumes of copies of deeds showing trackage locations (1868-1912); 48 volumes of dispatchers' diaries used at Norwich and noting the weather, accidents, and unusual occurrences on the Northern Division (1890-1893, 1896, 1898-1940); 19 volumes of engineers' survey books (c. 1910), which give specifications for improvements in track and structures; official notices of schedule and route changes (1948-1956); map and survey; timetable (1954); map and profile of the Pecksport Loop line. Chenango County, Madison County, Oneida County, Oswego County.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Helmer, William Floyd,1926-,; New York, Ontario, and Western Railway Co.
Subjects:
Railroads--New York (State)--Chenango County.; Railroads--New York (State)--Madison County.; Railroads--New York (State)--Oneida County.; Railroads--New York (State)--Oswego County.; Railroads--New York (State)--Maintenance and repair.; Railroads--New York (State)--Design and construction.; Railroads--New York (State)--Management.; Railroads--New York (State)--Surveying.; Railroads--New York (State)--Timetables.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Deed Books - 7 loose leaf volumes (that show trackage locations)
  - Chenango County, 1868-1895 (Box 1)
  - Chenango County, 1868-1912 (Box 1)
  - Madison County, 1868-1910 (Box 1)
  - Oneida County, 1868-1896 (Box 1)
  - Oswego County, 1868-1882 (Box 1)
  - Oswego County, 1868-1882 (Box 1)
  - Chenango County, 1869-1882 (Box 1)
- Diaries, 14 volumes 1890-1893, 1896, 1898-1906 (Box 2)
  Daily entries include brief weather report and any unusual occurence along the right of way (e.g. man killed by engine, wreckers working at some particular spot, etc.) Note: These and ones listed below used by dispatchers at Norwich controlling Northern Division trains.
- 19 notebooks used as engineer's survey books. (Box 2)
  Notebooks contain varied information - abutment descriptions, location sites photographed, surveying information, etc. Note: c. 1910, when line was being improved ...locates exactly and gives specifications for track and structures.
- Notices - 2-12, 14-16., 1948-1956 (Box 3)
  Official notices pertaining to schedule changes, changes in routing, etc. Also General Order #387, Rev. no. 1, July 1, 1952
- Timetable - N. 75 effective Sunday Apr. 25, 1954 Eastern Standard Time. (Box 3)
- "Analysis of Operations of the Rutland Railway Corporation as compared with the New York, Ontario, and Western Railway prepared by Lewis D. Freeman, trustee, N.Y., O. & W. Railway." 21 pp. Middletown, N.Y., May 14, 1956 (Box 3)
- Diaries, 23 volumes., 1907-1929 (Box 3)
- Diaries, 11 volumes., 1930-1940 (Box 4)
- Map and profile of the Pecksport Loop Line. (Box 4)
- Survey BR. 52, Utica, N.Y. (Proposed construction in Red), Aug. 1913 (Box 4)